Guide to the Justin R. Hartzog papers,1917-1966.
Hartzog, Justin R. papers,1917-1966.
- Projects
  - New Hampshire
    - Publications and other press materials
      - New Hampshire Society for the Protection of New Hampshire Forests The Flume Reservation. Franconia Notch. Lost River, Concord, N.H., 1938 (Box 15)
      - New Hampshire State Planning and Development Commission. New Hampshire, Concord, N.H., 1941 (Box 15)
      - The Piscataqua Regional Defense Area, 1942 (Box 15)
      - Public Recreation in New Hampshire, 1943 (Box 15)
      - The Great Bay Plain, 1945 (Box 15)
    - Works Progress Administration
      - Research Outlines (Box 15)
      - Progress Report #1488 (Box 15)
      - Project #346 report (Box 15)
      - Project #346 report (continued) (Box 16)
      - Project #864 Reports (formerly #346) (Box 16)
      - Progress Report, June, 1937 (Box 16)
      - Weekly Reports (Box 16)
      - Weekly Payroll Reports (Box 16)
  - New England Regional Planning Commission
    1935-1936: Member, Board of Consultants
    - Act to create New England Regional Planning Commission (Box 16)
    - Correspondence, 1934-1940 (Box 16)
    - Meetings and Conferences (Box 16)
  - Maine State Planning Board
    1934: Technical Consultant
    - Correspondence, 1934-1935 (Box 16)
    - Act to create Maine State Planning Board (Box 16)
    - Press Release, July, 1934 (Box 16)
  - Vermont State Planning Commission
    - Correspondence (Box 16)
    - Draft to create Vermont State Planning Commission (Box 16)
    - Highways, 1935 (Box 16)
    - Graphic Survey, 1935 (Box 16)
    - Progress Report, 1936 (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous pamphlets (Box 16)
    - Aerial photographs (Box 16)
  - Rhode Island
    - Rhode Island State Planning Board
      1943-1948: State Planning Board Consultant, National Resources Planning Board
      - Administrative files
        - Act to create Rhode Island State Planning Board, 1936 (Box 17)
        - Correspondence, 1938-1948 (Box 17)
        - Professional registration (Box 17)
        - Radio broadcast, June 10, 1939 (Box 17)
        - Planning - Zoning (Box 17)
        - Regional plans (Box 17)
        - Draft of the 4th Annual Report, 1938 (Box 17)
        - Mimeos, 1938 (Box 17)
        - Personnel - Office organization, 1939 (Box 17)
        - Analysis of state planning acts, 1939 (Box 17)
        - South county region (Box 17)
        - Junior Chamber of Commerce speech (Box 17)
        - Providence metropolitan region (Box 17)
        - Advisory Committee on Water Pollution (Box 17)
        - Minutes of State Planning Board (Box 17)
        - Progress Report, 1938-1939 (Box 17)
        - Summery of annual report (Box 17)
        - Roadside Control and Improvement Advisory Committee, 1939-1940 (Box 17)
        - Economic Development Committee, 1943 (Box 17)
        - Names and addresses, 1943 (Box 17)
        - State Planning Board duties, 1943 (Box 17)
        - State Planning Board minutes, 1943 (Box 17)
        - State Planning Board organization (Box 17)
        - State Planning Board technical program (Box 17)
        - Population data (Box 17)
        - Post-war program (Box 17)
        - Providence River Crossing I (Box 17)
        - Planning Conference (Box 17)
        - Resolution #56 (Box 17)
        - State Institutions, 1944 (Box 17)
        - State and Home School (Box 17)
        - Exeter School (Box 17)
        - Master Plan of Highways (Box 17)
        - Public works planning procedure (Box 17)
        - Rhode Island Port Authority (Box 17)
        - Additional highway facilities crossing the Providence River (Box 17)
        - State Planning Board Minutes (Box 17)
        - Topographical Survey (Box 17)
        - Jamestown-Newprt Bridge, 1945 (Box 17)
        - Warwick-East Greenwich By-Pass (Box 17)
        - Providence traffic survey (Box 17)
        - Aviation Committee minutes (Box 17)
        - Post-war planning (Box 17)
        - United Nations site study (Box 17)
        - 11th Annual Report of the Rhode Island State Planning Board (Box 17)
        - Master plan for thoroughfares, 1946 (Box 17)
        - Communities and seashores (Box 17)
        - Newspaper clippings (Box 17)
        - Rhode Island State College with master plans, 1944-1949 (Box 17)
        - Miscellaneous manuscript papers (Box 17)
        - State Planning Board minutes, 1938-1940; 1943-1948 (Box 18)
        - Minutes and report of Advisory Committee on Roadside Control and Development, 1939-1940 (Box 18)
        - Manual for Post-War Housing (Box 19)
        - Legislative material (Box 19)
        - Newspaper clippings (Box 19)
      - Special Committee Minutes
        - Aviation, 1943-1946 (Box 18)
        - Building Program, 1943-1946 (Box 18)
        - Advancement of Local Planning, 1943-1946 (Box 18)
        - Pollution Abatement, 1943-1946 (Box 18)
        - Transportation, 1943-1946 (Box 18)
      - Reports
        - Special Report #5: Preliminary Report of the Blackstone River, February 1936 (Box 18)
        - Special Report #6: Rhode Island Commercial Fisheries, March 1936 (Box 18)
        - Special Report #9: Rhode Island Water Resources, September 1936 (Box 18)
        - Special Report #11: Planning and Zoning in Rhode Island, April 1937 (Box 18)
        - Special Report #12: Agriculture in Rhode Island, June 1937 (Box 18)
        - Six Month Progress Report, January 1 - June 15, 1937, June 30, 1937 (Box 18)
        - Report on Land Uses of the Southern Seashore of the State of Rhode Island, January 1939 (Box 18)
          United States Department of the Interior
        - Preliminary Report of the Rhode Island Park, Parkway and Recreational Area Study, May 1939 (Box 18)
          United States Department of Agriculture and Conservation
        - Report on Relocation and Realignment of the Port Road (U.S. 1), July 24, 1939 (Box 18)
        - Data on the Pollution of Rivers in Rhode Island, August 3, 1939 (Box 18)
        - Research Resources in Rhode Island, September 1939 (Box 18)
        - Progress Report - Planning Activities in Rhode Island October 1938-December 1939, December 1939 (Box 18)
        - Report of the Advisory Committee on Water Pollution, March 3, 1940 (Box 19)
        - Study on the Desirability and Practicability of a Rim-Route By-pass about Providence, May 1940 (Box 19)
        - Recreation and Conservation Committee of the State Planning Board, December 1943 (Box 19)
        - Report for Study on Recreational Development - Ocean and Bay Shores of Rhode Island, September 1944 (Box 19)
        - Additional Highway Facilities Over the Providence River, 1944 (Box 19)
        - Advisability and Desirability of Constructing a Bridge from the Island of Conanicut to the Island of Rhode Island, 1945 (Box 19)
        - Traffic Congestion in the Apponaug - East Greenwich Area, 1945 (Box 19)
        - Preliminary Report on Highway Cut-off Proposal to Westerly Airport and Watch Hill, October 1945 (Box 19)
        - Airport Facilities in State of Rhode Island, December 1945 (Box 19)
        - Report on Rumford Rifle Range, April 1947 (Box 19)
        - Annual Reports, 1935-1942; 1944-1947 (Box 19)
    - Other Rhode Island Cities
      - Barrington Annual Report, 1945 (Box 19)
      - Lincoln, 1948 (Box 19)
  - United States Housing Authority (Department of the Interior)
    1935-1942: City Planning Consultant
    - General and administrative files.
      - Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 20)
      - Travel (Box 20)
      - First budget resolution (Box 20)
      - Application for financial assistance (Box 20)
      - Memoranda (Box 20)
      - Bulletins, January 1938 - December 1939 (Box 20)
      - Pamphlets and list of publications (Box 20)
      - Legislative material (Box 20)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box 20)
    - Cities
      - Outline of cites and projects (Box 20)
      - Boston, Massachusetts (Box 20)
      - Bridgeport, Connecticut (Box 20)
      - Cambridge, Massachusetts (Box 20)
      - Chicopee, Massachusetts (Box 20)
      - Fall River, Massachusetts (Box 20)
      - Hartford, Connecticut (Box 20)
      - Holyoke (Box 20)
      - Lowell, Massachusetts (Box 20)
      - New Bedford (Box 20)
      - New Haven, Connecticut (Box 20)
      - Norwalk, Connecticut (Box 20)
      - Preliminary reports of above cities (Box 20)
  - Greenhills, Ohio
    - Resettlement Administration (Department of Agriculture)
      1935-1940: Chief Town Planner. 1947- Town Planning Consultant.
      - Incoming Correspondence: Washington Office
        In chronological order within folder.
        - Hartzog (Box 21)
          Chief Town Planner
        - John S. Lansill (Box 21)
          Assistant Administrator and Director
        - R.W. Digges (Box 21)
          Senior Administrative Officer
        - Frederick Bigger (Box 21)
          Chief of Planning
        - Albert L. Miller (Box 21)
          Regional Coordinator
        - Roland A. Wank (Box 21)
          Chief Architect
        - W.A. Strong (Box 21)
          Assistant Chief Town Planner
        - G. Frank Cordner (Box 21)
          Assistant Chief Architect
        - William G. Powell (Box 21)
          Chief Engineer
        - L.A. Bonsteel (Box 21)
          Associate Engineer
        - A.R. Tibbits (Box 21)
          Chief Designer
        - C.H. Ramsdell (Box 21)
          Designer, Block Design
        - J.F. Whitney (Box 21)
          Designer, Open Space
        - J.P. Murrin (Box 21)
          Office Manager
        - Charles W. Ransler (Box 21)
          Resident Engineer
        - Lawrence H. Tucker (Box 21)
          Senior Clerk, Report Writer
        - Harry M. Price (Box 21)
          Chief Superintendent
        - Albert H. Field (Box 21)
          Field Supervisor
        - J.B. Corridon (Box 21)
          Progress Engineer
        - Carlton F. Sharpe (Box 21)
          Community Manager
        - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 21)
      - Correspondence: Personnel
        - Office Personnel (Box 21)
        - Appointments (Box 21)
        - Personnel Administration (Box 21)
        - Travel Authorization (Box 21)
        - Consultants - General (Box 21)
        - Consultants - Appointments (Box 21)
        - Consultants - Certification (Box 21)
        - Consultants - Reports (Box 21)
      - Correspondence general
        - Directories (Box 21)
        - Weekly Reports though December 31, 1936 (Box 21)
        - Terminations - General (Box 21)
        - Terminations - Town Planning (Box 21)
        - Terminations - Engineers (Box 21)
      - Consultants Reports
        - A.H. Alexander (Box 21)
        - Tracy B. Augur (Box 21)
        - Alfred LeFeber (Box 21)
        - John Nolan (Box 21)
        - C.T. Rice (Box 21)
        - Clarence S. Stein (Box 21)
      - Washington D.C. Material for all "Greenbelts"
        - Orders, Instructions, and Memoranda (Box 21)
        - Land Policy Circulars, February 1935 - April 1938 (Box 21)
        - List of Library Accessions (Box 22)
        - Semi-monthly Graphic Reports (Box 22)
        - Other Greenbelts (Box 22)
        - Telephone Directories (Box 22)
      - General administrative Files
        - Greenhills - Cincinnati (Box 22)
        - Project Organization (Box 22)
        - Management - C.F. Sharpe, Community Manager (Box 22)
        - Policy (Box 22)
        - Concepts of Project (Box 22)
        - Major Decisions (Box 22)
        - Land Acquisitions (Box 22)
        - Surveys (Box 22)
        - Accounts (Box 22)
        - Cost Estimates (Box 22)
        - Conferences (Box 22)
        - Meetings (Box 22)
      - Town Planning
        - General Working Papers (Box 22)
        - Town Planning Program (Box 22)
        - Town Planning Drawings (Box 22)
        - List Schedule (Box 22)
        - Approvals (Box 22)
        - Study Plans (Box 22)
        - Construction Plans (Box 22)
        - Recommendation Approvals (Box 22)
        - Miscellaneous Approvals (Box 22)
        - Sizes, numbering, terminology (Box 22)
        - Plans received (Box 22)
        - Plans prepared (Box 22)
        - Plans record (Box 22)
        - Plans graphic (Box 22)
        - Plans Issuing (Box 22)
        - Housing Buildings (Box 22)
        - Plans miscellaneous (Box 22)
        - Town planning instructions (Box 22)
        - Town planning section report (Box 22)
        - Town Planner Report, 1937 (Box 22)
      - Open Space Design
        - Landscape Architecture (Box 22)
        - Natural Development - General (Box 22)
        - Farm leases (Box 22)
        - Soil (Box 22)
        - Forestry (Box 22)
        - Agriculture (Box 22)
      - Utility Design
        - Water (Box 23)
        - Roads (Box 23)
        - Electricity (Box 23)
        - Fire Alarm System (Box 23)
        - Working papers for Black notebook (Box 23)
        - General (Box 23)
        - Sewer (Box 23)
        - Swimming Pool (Box 23)
        - Incinerator (Box 23)
        - Garbage Storage (Box 23)
        - Electric (Box 23)
        - Telephone (Box 23)
        - Gas (Box 23)
        - Sidewalks (Box 23)
      - Utility Design: Water Supply
        - Temperature Supply (Box 23)
        - Distribution (Box 23)
        - Service Meters (Box 23)
        - Construction Division (Box 23)
        - Legal (Box 23)
      - Utility Design: Reports
        - Streets and Pavements (Box 23)
        - Water Supply and Distribution (Box 23)
        - Sanitation and Storm Sewerage (Box 23)
        - Electricity and Telephone (Box 23)
      - Architecture: Volume 1
        - Labor Materials (Box 23)
        - Construction (Box 23)
        - Specifications (Box 23)
        - Architectural Recommendations (Box 23)
        - Heating (Box 23)
        - Commercial Center (Box 23)
        - Experimentation (Box 23)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 23)
        - Operation - Maintenance Reports (Box 23)
      - Architecture: Reports
        - Business Center Report (Box 23)
        - Specifications for Construction of a Community Building (Box 23)
        - Plan Reproductions - Constructions I - General (Box 23)
        - Architectural Sketches (Box 23)
        - Topographical Photostats (Box 23)
        - House Plan Types (Box 23)
        - Inspection Division Semi-monthly reports (Box 23)
      - General: Reports
        - On Making Reproductions (Box 23)
        - Outline for Project Report (Box 23)
        - Overall Report on Entire Project, December 1937 (Box 23)
        - Project Planning Principals (Box 23)
        - Weekly Statistical (Box 24)
      - Research: Reports
        - Probably Economic Life (Box 23)
        - Population Survey (Box 23)
        - Government, Taxes, Budget, Eventual Ownership (Box 23)
        - Living Habits of Potential Tenants (Box 23)
        - Population (Box 24)
        - Schools (Box 24)
        - Transportation (Box 24)
      - Publicity
        - Speeches (Box 24)
        - Resettlement Administration Releases (Box 24)
        - Other Releases (Box 24)
        - Newspaper Clippings (Box 24)
        - Articles (Box 24)
        - Manual and News bulletins (Box 24)
        - Pamphlets (Box 24)
      - Photographs
        - Office Staff (Box 24)
        - Aerial (Box 24)
        - Progress (Box 24)
    - Other Departments (not Resettlement Administration)
      - Hamilton County Regional Planning Commission (Box 24)
      - Hamilton County Commissioners (Box 24)
      - Hamilton County Park District (Box 24)
      - Cincinnati Public Recreation Commission (Box 24)
      - City of Cincinnati (Box 24)
      - State Highway Administration (Box 24)
      - State Department of Health (Box 24)
      - Boy Scouts (Box 24)
      - Legal (Box 24)
      - Ohio Municipal Government (Box 24)
      - Ohio Constitution (Box 24)
      - Ohio Platting (Box 24)
      - Cincinnati City Planning Commission (Box 24)
      - United State Department of Commerce (Box 24)
    - Greenhills, Ohio
      1946-1963: Town Planning Consultant
      - Second Anniversary Pamphlet, 1940 (Box 25)
      - Working papers, 1946 (Box 25)
      - 8th Anniversary Pamphlet, 1946 (Box 25)
      - Streets, Houses, Housetypes, 1946 (Box 25)
      - Greenbelt Towns Committee, 1947 (Box 25)
      - Report and Program for Extension in Development (Box 25)
      - Zoning, 1948 (Box 25)
      - Zoning Ordinances (Box 25)
      - Kenneth Hammond Incorporated, 1952 (Box 25)
      - Voght, Ivers, Seaman and Associates - North Greenhills, 1953 (Box 25)
      - North Greenhills Project, 1953 (Box 25)
      - Greenbelt of Greenhills, 1953 (Box 25)
      - Working Papers, 1955-1957 (Box 25)
      - Hammond, Kenneth, 1958 (Box 25)
      - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 25)
      - School Building Needs, 1960 (Box 25)
      - Files made available to attorneys in suit of December 1961, 1961 (Box 25)
      - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 25)
      - Forest Park: The Kanter Corporation (Box 25)
      - Court Action, 1960 and 1963 (Box 25)
      - Publicity (Box 25)
  - Division of Defense Housing Coordination (Office for Emergency Management)
    1940-1942: Regional Coordinator Special Consultant for Region I - New England
    - Executive Order to Create (Box 26)
    - Correspondence (Box 26)
      In ring binder
    - Appointments, services, travel (Box 26)
    - Working Papers (Box 26)
    - Manual for Planning of Defense Housing - drafts (Box 26)
    - Manual of Operations (Box 26)
    - Locality Occupancy Program (Box 26)
    - Las Vegas Magnesium Plant
      - Correspondence (Box 26)
      - Reports (Box 26)
      - Working Papers (Box 26)
      - Aerial photos (Box 26)
    - Region I Reports
      - Connecticut (Box 26)
      - Maine (Box 26)
      - Massachusetts (Box 26)
      - New Hampshire (Box 26)
      - Rhode Island (Box 26)
      - Vermont (Box 26)
    - Memoranda
      - Coordinator's Orders (Box 26)
      - Agenda (Box 26)
      - Memoranda (Box 26)
      - Schedules (Box 26)
      - Addresses (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Legislative Material (Box 26)
      - Pamphlets (Box 26)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 26)
  - Division of Defense Housing Coordination (Office for Emergency Management)
    1942-1943: Chief City Planning Consultant
    - Administrative files
      - Correspondence, January 18, 1943-August 28, 1944 (Box 27)
      - Memoranda to Directors and Chief Underwriters of all Field Offices (Box 27)
      - Travel and Expense Vouchers (Box 27)
      - Forms (Box 27)
      - Manual of Policy and Procedure, 1943 (Box 28)
      - Transcripts (Box 28)
      - Lanham Development Manual (Box 28)
      - Newspaper Clippings (Box 28)
      - Other Agencies (includes Office of Defense Transportation) (Box 28)
    - Operating Manual
      - Programming (Box 27)
      - Technical (Box 27)
      - Urban Planning (Box 27)
      - Research and Statistics (Box 27)
      - Racial Relations (Box 27)
      - Administrations (Box 27)
      - Organization (Box 27)
      - Procedure (Box 27)
      - Personnel (Box 27)
      - Training (Box 27)
      - Fiscal and Budget (Box 27)
      - Administrative Services (Box 27)
      - Office Practice (Box 27)
      - Interpretation of Legislation (Box 27)
      - Public Relations (Box 27)
    - Cities Consulted
      - Baltimore (Box 27)
      - Beaver Country, Pennsylvania (Box 27)
      - Boston (Box 27)
      - Buffalo (Box 27)
      - Dayton (Box 27)
      - Detroit (Box 27)
      - Fort Worth (Box 27)
      - Freeport, Texas (Box 27)
      - Hampton Roads, Virginia (Box 27)
      - Hartford (Box 27)
      - La Porte, Indiana (Box 27)
      - Las Vegas (see also Division of Defense Housing) (Box 27)
      - Los Angeles (Box 27)
      - Morgantown, West Virginia (Box 27)
      - New Orleans (Box 27)
      - Ogden, Utah (Box 27)
      - Portland, Maine (Box 27)
      - Portsmouth, New Hampshire (Box 27)
      - Quincy, Massachusetts (Box 27)
      - Quincy-Bingham (Box 27)
      - Tampa (Box 27)
    - War Housing Program
      - Preparation (Box 28)
      - Locality Analysis (Box 28)
      - Past and Future (Box 28)
      - Monthly Progress Reports (Box 28)
      - Post War Housing Discussion Group (Box 28)
      - Post War Legislation (Box 28)
      - Mimeo, Reports, Papers (Box 28)
      - Memoranda
        - Newsletters (Box 28)
        - Technical Division Standards (Box 28)
        - Staff (Box 28)
        - Regional Circulars (Box 28)
        - Circulars (Box 28)
        - Abstracts (Box 28)
        - Digests (Box 28)
        - Weekend Releases (Box 28)
        - General (Box 28)
        - Administrative (Box 28)
        - Office Practice (Box 28)
        - Urban Studies (Box 28)
        - Technical Divisions (Box 28)
  - Court Cases
    - Ohio Supreme Court: Greenhills Home Owners Corporation, plaintiff vs. Village of Greenhills, Ohio, defendant (Box 1)
      Appeal from Court of Appeals. Record Volumes I, II, III
    - Ohio Supreme Court: Brief of Defendant-Appellants, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Ohio Supreme Court: Reply Brief, 1964 (Box 1)
    - United States Supreme Court: Greenhills Home Owners Corporation, petitioner vs. Village of Greenhills, Ohio, respondents, c. 1966 (Box 1)
    - Ohio Court of Common Pleas: Greenhills Home Owners Corporation, relator vs. Village of Greenhills, Ohio, respondents. Deposition of John Taylor Egan. (Box 29)
      Unbound stenographic transcript (copy)
    - Testimony of Bernard Grove (Box 29)
      Typescript carbon
- Oversized Drawings and Plans